Be careful out there today. I'm not scared of sharks. It's something else. Stop freaking me out.
This is from a concept movie I made entirely inside OpenArts' new smart shot tool, which uses
GPT Image 2 and Sedance 2.0 to turn your ideas into cinematic movies. Today's video is sponsored by OpenArts.
The storyboards generated in GPT Image 2 lay out your characters, shots, camera moves,
and color palette. Then Sedance 2 takes that sheet and then generates a video that can be up to 15
seconds long. I'll show you how to use smart shot to go beyond just generating individual clips
to creating multiple clips that have consistent characters and environments that you can edit
together into short films. I'll show you some tips to save credits as you're generating.
For this first one, I'm really going to push the capabilities of this text rendering. So I'm
going to paste this story idea. I'm not going to use any characters or objects this time,
and I'm not going to use an environment. So there's sheet quality, low medium high, and there's
output quality with different resolutions. Let's just try the different sheets. Let's do this as
a low quality sheet and then do it as a medium quality sheet and then a high quality sheet.
So let's take a look at the low quality version first. On the billboard truck, the text is rendered
correctly. This light on college application looks good, the phone number looks good,
but you can see it's not perfect on all of them. So we've got our front facing, a side facing,
and a back view. There is the facial close-up, the profile, and I'm not sure why we need that.
I guess it's at the costume detail. So it has this plan. I'm not sure how closely this plan
actually ties to this storyboard, but as long as AI understands what it needs to do with this,
I guess that makes sense. Now that we've seen the low quality one, let's go to the medium quality.
The character looks a little bit better, in my opinion. Here's the diagram. I wonder if this one's
any better. So we've got much more legible text here. It says call disconnected. The number you've
dialed is not in service. I do like the fact that we can see it here. It's clear. It's slightly
out of focus here, but we still have the right numbers and everything is in the right place.
And then it's putting his picture on the billboard. So this billboard is not on the truck,
and that might be a problem with my prompt. Here is the high quality one. It's a better outfit,
maybe because that's almost the clothes I wear. So we're getting a lot more detail in this top
down view than we had in the original one. And it also knows that the billboard progresses here.
So it's really interesting. The last one we had that billboard that wasn't on the truck,
and here it knows to keep it on the truck. I was wondering about this. If it would be showing
everything on the phone, or if it would do these overlays, and I love that it does this message
overlay. So for the preview sheets, that's the difference between the low quality,
the medium quality, and the high quality. C-dance 2 is very strict about celebrity likenesses.
And GPT image 2 is leaning in on its training data, which is mostly famous people. So I did the
IP safety check, so I couldn't turn it into a video. So if you're just generating a video here,
I don't know if you really need to use this check IP safety, because it costs 20 credits,
and if your video doesn't go through, the credits are refunded anyway. Maybe someone has a reason
that they would use this, but for me, I would rather just, if I like the storyboard, I would just
generate it. I don't know if these count as a secret promptacks, but two things that I did that I
noticed worked was describing a character's face as unconventional, or unconventionally attractive.
And I feel like that forces the model to dig a little deeper. And the other thing I did was
just put an age in there, like, like 38-year-old woman. That might be because she's a 38-year-old
surfer, and there's not a lot of celebrities that match that. But my theory is that when you use
an age, I'm guessing that celebrities aren't tagged by age in the model. Just two things to try.
Unconventional, or unconventionally attractive, and give them an age. Here's the version of the
movie that passed the IP safety. There's a few things like the number is correct here,
but it's not correct there. And he lied on his coolage application. I tried to do this same
scene with a different cinematic style and using the medium resolution of 720. I actually like the
look of it a little bit more, but the text didn't come out quite right. So if you're doing a video
that has a lot of complicated text, I'd recommend using high resolution for both the preview sheet
and the video. Speaking of our 38-year-old surfer, I'm going to do a high quality sheet with a low
quality video, just to save some credits. And then I'm going to do a different high quality sheet
with a high quality video. So we can compare the two of those. First, let's just compare the sheets.
So we've got our full body profiles here, a front side and back. We've got a close-up of the face,
a profile. And then there's some details around the board and our color grade. We've got our
camera diagram here and then the storyboard.
So I've generated a new storyboard and I'm going to generate a high quality video from that one.
I like how this diagram shows. Here's where the submerged city is. Here's where the surfer
is. Here's where the cameras are. To answer my question from before, this is camera 4 looking
directly at her. If it's looking here, it's not going to see the city and in here cut 4, we see the
city. So I'm not sure how closely it's following this diagram, but it seems like maybe it's getting
some direction from it.
The nice thing about doing it in two steps, where you first generate the preview sheet and then
the video, is that you can double check the sheet to make sure everything looks good. So for instance,
I got lazy and just pasted it in a prompt and hit generate. And I didn't even look at the storyboard.
If I had, I might have noticed that the dead makes a terrible mistake here. The nice thing is it's
seedant. So there's no actual physical pain that you see. So this handoff of the knife is probably
something I could have caught in the preview sheet. Now even if you do check the preview sheets,
if you're doing something that's really complicated logically, like I'm having a robot hold one arm
with their other hand, that's really hard for AI to figure out. So let's look at that one really
quick. But before we do that, let's look at this one one more time.
I wanted to do a video where I uploaded some of my favorite characters. So I used a character reference
sheet of this Android. And then this guy who I used as a reference in my movie, Jettie tsunami.
So based on my prompt, it knew to change the outfit and it knew to change one arm holding the other
arm. But when I look at this storyboard, I can tell maybe this isn't going to work. What I decided to
do was just go into images and then generate an image of the character already in that outfit
and already with one arm holding the other arm that gives GPT image to less to figure out when
it creates this storyboard. This one looks a lot better. But let's see how well C-Dance 2
takes this storyboard from GPT image 2 and translates the confusing physical logic of what's
happening in this scene. So I had something very specific in mind. Let's say you saw this without
the prompt. You would just see this very compelling shot. You wouldn't be worried that the name made
no sense. You'd see that reaction and everything's very consistent in the clip itself. So even though
it doesn't match the storyboard that we got, everything is consistent within the video itself. So
there's a mistranslation between GPT image 2 and C-Dance 2 for scenes like this that might be a
little more logically complicated for the model to figure out what's happening. Let's go back to
our surfer. I have this really great scene and I want to turn it into a story. I can just show what
happened before and after this event. So I'm going to bring our Android back for this and I'm going
to use a consistent environment or location. So I went back to images to generate this mid-century
lini with this amazing view and now I can generate two different scenes to book end that surfing scene.
This isn't a complete movie. It feels like something you might see at the beginning of a movie.
Be careful out there today. I'm not scared of sharks. So that's the advantage of using this tool
is that you can create consistent characters in consistent environments and get these amazing
looking cinematic results. I'll also generate a little bit of music to tie those scenes together a
little bit more. And if you are looking to save credits by doing it at 480 instead of 1080,
you can always go in an upscale to 1080. So you're just upscaling the resolution of the 480 version.
The 1080 version has a lot more detail and a lot more going on with the physics and the lighting
and the realism of the characters. But C-Dance is a really expensive model. So if you're just playing
around, I recommend doing 480. If you need it to be 1080, you could upscale it. Thank you for
watching. I hope this was helpful. I hope seeing these experiments helped you save on some of your
own credits. Go make some cool storyboards and movies in open art.
Be careful out there today. I'm not scared of sharks. It's something else. Stop freaking me out.
You...
They want... who wants what?
The extraterrestrials living under our ocean want to speak with... you.